[
    {
      "question": "What is the Home Secretary responsible for?",
      "answer": " Crime; policing and immigration",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do any Church of England bishops sit in the House of Lords?",
      "answer": " Yes",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is the status of St Helena?",
      "answer": " British Overseas Territory; not part of the UK",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "When did Ireland become a republic?",
      "answer": " 1949; following the Republic of Ireland Act 1948",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Under which king did the Anglo-Saxon kingdoms in England unite to defeat the Vikings?",
      "answer": " King Alfred the Great",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "When was the Magna Carta created?",
      "answer": " 1215; King John",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "How many members does a jury have in England; Wales and Northern Ireland?",
      "answer": " 12. The seeds of the modern justice system were sown by Henry II (1154-1189); who established a jury of 12 local knights to settle disputes over the ownership of land.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is St Patrick’s day a public holiday in Northern Ireland?",
      "answer": " True. Scotland and Northern Ireland have their patron saint’s day as an official holiday (although in Scotland not all businesses and offices will close).",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was the first person in England to print books using a printing press?",
      "answer": " William Caxton; 15th century",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "What did the Scottish John Logie Baird develop?",
      "answer": " The television in the 1920s.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does Wales have its own esrtablished church?",
      "answer": " False. There is no established Church in Wales or Northern Ireland.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "What is New Year’s Eve called in Scotland?",
      "answer": " Hogmanay",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who was supported by clansmen from the Scottish highlands and raised and army in 1745?",
      "answer": " Bonnie Prince Charlie",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which jubilee did Queen Elizabeth II celebrate in 2012?",
      "answer": " Diamond Jubilee (60 years as queen).",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the last battle between Great Britain and France?",
      "answer": "  The Battle of Waterloo was fought on Sunday; 18 June 1815; near Waterloo in the United Kingdom of the Netherlands; now in Belgium.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "How often are general elections held in the UK?",
      "answer": " MPs are elected at a General Election; which is held at least every five years.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "When did women get the right to vote at the same age as men?",
      "answer": " 1928",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "How old do you have to be to stand as MP?",
      "answer": " 18",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who developed the radar?",
      "answer": " Robert Watson-Watt",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "By law; which TWO types of media have to give a balanced coverage of all political parties and equal time to rival viewpoints before an election?",
      "answer": " By law; radio and television coverage of the political parties must be balanced and so equal time has to be given to rival viewpoints.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "What king was defeated by Oliver Cromwell during the Civil War and hid in an oak tree before escaping to Europe?",
      "answer": " Charles II",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the 'Glorious Revolution'?",
      "answer": " In 1688 William of Orange was asked by Protestants to invade England and proclaim himself king. But when William reached England there was no resistance and he took over the throne.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "What was the Boer War (1899-1902)?",
      "answer": " The Second Boer War (also known as the Boer War; the Anglo–Boer War or the South African War) was a conflict fought between the British Empire and the two Boer Republics over the Empire's influence in Southern Africa. Boers: descendants of the Dutch-speaking Free Burghers of the eastern Cape frontier in Southern Africa.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Who minted the first coins in Britain?",
      "answer": " The people of the Iron Age made the first coins to be minted in Britain",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which king was executed in 1649?",
      "answer": " Charles I",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which two political parties formed a coalition in 2010?",
      "answer": " In May 2010 the Conservative and Liberal Democrat parties formed a coalition and the leader of the Conservative Party - David Cameron - became Prime Minister.",
      "rating": "5"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which court deals with minor criminal offences in Scotland?",
      "answer": " In Scotland minor criminal offences go to a Justice of the Peace Court.",
      "rating": "5"
    }
   ]